const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 56-year-old man was taking medications for osteoporosis secondary to hyperparathyroidism and recently was diagnosed with osteosarcoma. Which of the following medications he must be using?","answers":[{"option":"Cinacalcet","bool":false},{"option":"Strontium","bool":false},{"option":"Fosamax","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false},{"option":"Teriparatide","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 23-year-old woman has a routine health status examination. Her body mass index is 22. Laboratory studies show fasting plasma glucose is 120 mg/dL. Urinalysis shows mild glucosuria, but no ketonuria or proteinuria. She has no detectable insulin autoantibodies. Her father was similarly affected at age 20. She is most likely to have a mutation in a gene encoding for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT4","bool":false},{"option":"MHC DR","bool":false},{"option":"Glucagon","bool":false},{"option":"Glucokinase","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 42-year-old man presents with polyuria and polydipsia for the past 4 months. On physical examination, there are no specific findings. Laboratory findings include serum Na+ 155 mol/L; K+ 3.9 mol/L; Cl- 111 mmol/L; glucose 84 mg/dL; creatinine 1 mg/dL. The specific gravity of urine is 1.002 (low). Which of the following is most likely to be deficient in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Corticotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Antidiuretic hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Melatonin","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 40-year-old woman notices that her gloves from the previous winter do not fit her hands. Her friends remark that her facial features have changed over the past year and that her voice seems deeper. On physical examination, . Her blood pressure is 140/90 mm Hg. She has coarse facial features. Examination of the foot shows an increased amount of soft tissue beneath the sole. Which of the following statements is more appropriate for her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Increased serum cortisol level","bool":false},{"option":"Increased serum TSH level","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal glucose tolerance test result","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of growth hormone suppression","bool":true},{"option":"Elevated serum prolactin level","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A middle-aged man always remains dirty. He always complains about hearing voices saying Mr. Xavier is against you. What is the false perception of something in the absence of an external stimuli known as?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Delusion","bool":false},{"option":"Grandiosity","bool":false},{"option":"Hallucination","bool":true},{"option":"Illusion","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"Which of the following terms is used to describe a false belief that cannot be corrected?","answers":[{"option":"Grandiosity","bool":false},{"option":"Mania","bool":false},{"option":"Delusion","bool":true},{"option":"Hallucination","bool":false},{"option":"Illusion","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"While picking cotton from cotton pods, a farmer's wife develops nausea and dyspnea. When brought to the hospital, she is diagnosed with organophosphate poisoning. Which of the following is the most likely route of entry of the poison?","answers":[{"option":"Inhalation","bool":false},{"option":"Contact with mucuous membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Contact with intact skin","bool":true},{"option":"Gastrointestinal","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"To differentiate between true and feigned insanity, a medical officer will notice which of the following in a patient who is truly insane?","answers":[{"option":"Remains aggressive all the time","bool":true},{"option":"Feels tired soon","bool":false},{"option":"Has facial expressions that do not match with emotions","bool":false},{"option":"Is abusive","bool":false},{"option":"Minds repeated examination","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 25-year-old man was traveling by train when he was offered a samosa with a cup of tea by a fellow passenger. After an hour he became aggressive and started talking irrelevantly and picking thread from his clothes. On examination, he was found to have dilated pupils, dysarthria, dry hot skin, and drunken gait. What is the poison responsible for this man's presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Ice crystal","bool":false},{"option":"Charas","bool":false},{"option":"Amphetamine","bool":false},{"option":"Dhatura","bool":true},{"option":"Opium","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 25-year-old addict was spraying insecticide in the fields for the last three hours when he suddenly developed shortness of breath and cough. On examination he was found to have miosis, lacrimation, and salivation. What is the antidote of this poison?","answers":[{"option":"Physostigmine","bool":false},{"option":"BAL","bool":false},{"option":"Nalorphine","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male patient was diagnosed as a case of hyperthyroidism and the treating physician suggested him an anti-thyroid drug. Which of the following drugs inhibits the organification step of thyroid hormone synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Carbimazole","bool":false},{"option":"Iodides","bool":false},{"option":"Radioactive iodine","bool":false},{"option":"Thiocynate","bool":false},{"option":"Methimazole","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 60-year-old female with multinodular goiter is scheduled for a near total thyroidectomy. Which of the drugs will be administered for 10-14 days before surgery to reduce the vascularity of her thyroid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Prednisone","bool":false},{"option":"Lugol's solution","bool":true},{"option":"Radioactive iodine","bool":false},{"option":"Levothyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Liothyronine","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 40-year-old woman presents with an increasing feeling of fullness in her neck for the past 7 months. On physical examination, her thyroid gland is enlarged and nodular. A fine needle aspiration biopsy of the thyroid is done, and she undergoes thyroidectomy. Gross examination of the thyroid shows a multicentric thyroid neoplasm; microscopically, the neoplasm is composed of polygonal to spindle-shaped cells forming nests and trabeculae. There is a prominent, pink hyaline stroma. Which of the following immunohistochemical stains is most likely to be useful in the diagnosis of this neoplasm?","answers":[{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":true},{"option":"Vimentin","bool":false},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Cytokeratin","bool":false},{"option":"Cathepsin D","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 29-year-old female has a TSH of 13.5 mlU/L (normal: 0.5 to 4.7 mlU/L) Which of the following agents is most appropriate to treat this TSH abnormality?","answers":[{"option":"Propylthiouracil","bool":false},{"option":"Liothyronine","bool":false},{"option":"Liotrix","bool":false},{"option":"Levothyroxine","bool":true},{"option":"Dextrothyroxine","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 44-year-old man sees his physician because of a ''lump'' on the left side of his neck. Physical examination shows a non-tender nodule on the left lobe of the thyroid gland. A cervical node is also enlarged and non-tender. Laboratory studies show no thyroid autoantibodies in his serum, and the T4 and TSH levels are normal. A thyroidectomy is performed. Microscopic examination of the thyroid shows the features of papillary carcinoma. Which of the following is most likely to contribute to the development of the thyroid nodule in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenal medullary pheochromocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic dietary iodine deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Consumption of goitrogens","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine kinase receptor gene mutation","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"This medication is used to treat hyperparathyroidism in patients with chronic renal failure. It works by mimicking the role of calcium in the blood and tricks the parathyroid gland into stopping the secretion of parathyroid hormone (PTH). Which of the following medications matches with this description?","answers":[{"option":"Fosamax","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Sensipar","bool":true},{"option":"Carbimazole","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common side effect of insulin therapy in type 1 diabetic patients?","answers":[{"option":"Dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 14-year-old boy with type 1 diabetes is brought to the hospital complaining of dizziness. Laboratory findings show severe hypoglycemia and ketoacidosis. Which of the following drugs should be administered to achieve rapid control of severe ketoacidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Regular insulin","bool":true},{"option":"NPH insulin suspension","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin glargine","bool":false},{"option":"Tolbutamide","bool":false},{"option":"Glyburide","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 73-year-old woman presents to the emergency department with complaints of fatigue, sluggishness, weight gain, cold intolerance, dry skin, and muscle weakness for the last 2 months. When initiating T4 therapy for an elderly patient with long standing hypothyroidism, small doses are administered in the beginning. This is done to avoid which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Overstimulation of the heart","bool":true},{"option":"A flare-up of exopthalmus","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A professor wants to award a prize to his students on their remarkable performance in the exam. There were five students who are tied for the first position while the professor had to choose only one student among the 5. Which of the following would be a fair technique, which will help the professor choose one out of the five eligible students?","answers":[{"option":"Convenience sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified random sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Quota sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Simple random sampling","bool":true},{"option":"Consecutive sampling","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A researcher wants to select an unbiased sample, which will account for the various ethnicities residing in the area. Which of the following techniques will help the professor to recruit such a sample?","answers":[{"option":"Simple random sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic random sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Quota sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified random sampling","bool":true},{"option":"Consecutive sampling","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A professor was giving a lecture on the significance of sample size estimation. He emphasized that a large sample size will help to find whether the difference between two or more groups exists in reality. Which of the following was the professor referring to?","answers":[{"option":"Power","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha error","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 error","bool":false},{"option":"P-value","bool":false},{"option":"Confidence interval","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A researcher wants to select an unbiased national-level sample, which will account for the various ethnicities residing in Pakistan. He received a milllion dollar grant to find out the prevalence of hemoglobinopathies in Pakistan. Which of the following techniques will help the professor recruit such a sample?","answers":[{"option":"Cluster sampling","bool":true},{"option":"Purposive sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Consecutive sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Quota sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Convenience sampling","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A group of medical students submits the plan for their research project to the institutional board. This plan contains background, objectives, hypothesis, methodology, consent form, questionnaire, and references. Which of the following best defines this plan for research given in the above scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Synopsis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Rationale","bool":false},{"option":"Introduction","bool":false},{"option":"Abstract","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A group of researchers write a research proposal and in it they gave an explanation of the fundamental reasons for their research. Which of the following best describes the justification of the research work?","answers":[{"option":"Operational definition","bool":false},{"option":"Rationale","bool":true},{"option":"Objective","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Introduction","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 6-month-old infant is brought to the outpatient department with by his parents with concerns about his general health. According to them, he was born at term at home with good weight and length but had a history of prolonged jaundice. Now they feel he is not active; he sleeps more and feeds less. There is also a history of constipation. On examination, the anterior fontanelle is open and large and the posterior fontanelle is still open. Which is the most likely investigation that will help in the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Karyotyping","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone level","bool":false},{"option":"Total bilirubin level","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin-like growth factor level","bool":false},{"option":"TSH level","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 13-year-old girl presented with her parents with complaints of rapid decreased in her weight. According to the parents she has also complain of tremulousness, headache, mood disturbances, behavioral swings, difficulties with sleep, decrease in attention span, hyperactivity and a decline in school performance. On examination her eyes are protruded with lid lag. Her skin is smooth and flushed with excessive sweating. She is tachycardic with increased systolic blood pressure and a widened pulse pressure. What should be the treatment of choice to treat her underlying condition?","answers":[{"option":"Methimazole","bool":true},{"option":"Radioiodine ablation","bool":false},{"option":"Propylthiouracil","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Near-total thyroidectomy","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"During embryogenesis of the pituitary gland, Rathke's pouch will lead to the formation of which of the following structures of the pituitary gland?","answers":[{"option":"Pars distalis","bool":true},{"option":"Pars nervosa","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pars intermedia","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of third ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 30-year-old woman complains of increasing weight gain, fatigability, depression and poor memory for last three months. She is noticed to have a pale complexion, dry scaly skin and high blood pressure. What is the most important investigation you will advise?","answers":[{"option":"Electrocardiogram","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function tests (LFTs)","bool":false},{"option":"Fasting lipid profile","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid stimulating hormone","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"In case of untreated, primary hypothyroidism, the thyroid function tests best correspond to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increased free T4, Decreased TSH, Increased T3","bool":false},{"option":"Increased free T4, Decreased TSH, Decreased T3","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased free T4, Increased TSH, Decreased T3","bool":true},{"option":"Increased free T4, Increased TSH, Increased reversed T3","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased free T4, Decreased or normal TSH, Decreased T3","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"When considering thyroid hormone replacement in case of primary hypothyroidism, which of the following precautions should be remembered?","answers":[{"option":"Thyroxine should be stopped as soon as person becomes euthyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid hormone needs to be replaced for three months","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine tablet needs to be taken empty stomach in the morning","bool":true},{"option":"Elderly people should be started at a higher doses of thyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid hormone pill should be taken with breakfast","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 66-year-old woman is complaining of abdominal pain, constipation and polyuria. In the past, she underwent renal stone surgery. On examination, her blood pressure is 145/77mmHg and pulse is 98/min. Her fasting glucose and kidney function are normal but her calcium is found to be elevated at 13.05 mg/dL (NR 8.5-11.0). What is the most likely cause of her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D intoxication","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone excess","bool":false},{"option":"Primary hyperparathyrodism","bool":true},{"option":"Use of thiazide diuretics","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 26-year-old woman is complaining of abnormal tingling sensation in her hands and feet. For the last 2 years, a neurologist has been treating her for seizure disorder. On, examination, her blood pressure is 125/77mmHg and pulse is 98/min. Her investigations show: Calcium= 6.5 (7.5-8.5 mg/dl)\r\nPhosphate = 4.8 (2.5-4.0 mg/dl). What investigation will you do?","answers":[{"option":"Serum albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Serum parathyroid hormone levels","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin D levels","bool":false},{"option":"Serum phenytoin levels","bool":false},{"option":"MRI brain","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 40-year-old female with occasional complaints of dysuria and polyuria, presents with body aches and fatigue and the following labs: PTH 103 pg/ml (10-65), Ca 8.2 mg/dl (8.5-10.0), Phosphate 4.0 mmol/L (2.5-5.0), Albumin 4.4 mg/dl (2.5-5.5), Alkaline phosphatase 243 mg/dl (< 125), Vitamin D 8.0 ng/mL (> 30), 1,25 hydroxyvitamin D 7.0 pg/ml (18-78). What is the most likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Primary hyperparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary hyperparathyroidism","bool":true},{"option":"Familial hypocalciuric hypercalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy associated hypercalcemia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 30-year-old woman presents to the outpatient clinic with palpitations, weight loss and excessive sweating for almost 5-6 months. She cannot concentrate on carrying out her daily activities especially looking after her children. Recently, she has also developed pain in both eyes and her friend told her that one of her eyes has become more prominent than the other. What is the most likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hashimoto thyroiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Graves' disease","bool":true},{"option":"Toxic nodular goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Generalized anxiety disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 22-year-old male presents to the clinic with weight loss, diarrhea, and tremors for 2 months. He complains of excessive sweating and palpitations whenever he commutes to his office in the morning. He smokes 1 pack of cigarettes per day. He later suffers from Hashimoto's thyroiditis. His primary physician orders the following labs and refers him to you. TSH: 0.002 mIU/L (0.4-2). Serum T4: 23.8 ng/ml (6.5-11.5). What is the interpretation of his lab results?","answers":[{"option":"Multinodular goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Overt hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Overt hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Iodine toxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrotoxicosis","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2023","question":"A 27-year-old female undergoes total thyroidectomy for multinodular goiter. During this operation, the inferior thyroid artery is ligated. Which of the following nerves is intimately related to this artery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Internal laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"External laryngeal nerve","bool":false}]}]
export default arr